AGENT-READY LOCAL MEDIA
One URL. One exact file path.
No terminal scraping. No guessing after conversion.
YOU
Use lyt to download this permitted video at the best available quality,
keep it under 2 GB, and tell me the exact final file path.
CODEX / CLAUDE
I'll use lyt's JSON result, safe playlist defaults,
and a hard file-size guard.
REAL LYT RUN
$ lyt --video --max-filesize 2G --json "URL"
[download] 100%   lyt-permitted-source.mp4
MACHINE-READABLE RESULT
schema   "lyt.result.v1"
ok       true
status   "downloaded"
files    "C:\\Users\\Public\\Videos\\lyt-demo-final\\
lyt-permitted-source [lyt-permitted-source].mp4"
DONE
Exact path returned.
The file stays local. The agent knows exactly where it landed.
BUILT FOR CODEX + CLAUDE CODE
Give your agent a dependable local media tool.
npm install --global @tanattv/lyt
github.com/TanaTTV/lyt